Preston Prince

(940) 300-9495 prestonprince 18@gmail.com Github LinkedIn Personal Site

SKILLS React, Redux, JavaScript, Python, Express, Flask, Sequelize, SQLAlchemy, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, SQL, Git

PROJECTS

Rocket Pilled (React, Redux, Flask, Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, HTML5, CSS3)

Live Site | Github

A match-making web application where Rocket League players can create teams with each other, post matches, and compete head to head to earn experience points and climb the leaderboards.

- Designed the entire web application with custom css in order to provide a fluid and snappy user interface.
- Utilized **Redux** to organize and keep track of data from the **backend**, improving the application's overall performance.

Hangers Academy (Python, JavaScript, React, Redux, CSS3, Flask, SQLAlchemy, HTML5)

Live Site | Github

A chat-based web application inspired by Discord, built with React, Redux, Python, Flask, HTML5, and CSS3.

- Communicated effectively with three peers in a team environment in order to efficiently delegate tasks.
- Interpreted **SQLAlchemy** documentation to maximize interaction efficiency with the database.

BingusBnB (React, Redux, Express, Node, JavaScript, Sequelize, CSS3, HTML5)

Live Site | Github

An AirBnB clone built with React, Redux, Express, HTML, and CSS.

- Connected a React frontend to an Express backend, applying Redux to ensure validation of data.
- Leveraged **Git** workflow in order to keep work organized and easily trackable.

EXPERIENCE

La Finca Coffee & Bakery

Frisco, Texas

Barista / Food Runner / Busser

November 2021- March 2022

- Delivered food and drink items to > 300 customers daily, ensuring 94% customer satisfaction.
- Educated customers daily on coffee origins and processes, forming a strong bond between employee and customer.

Pie Five Pizza Co Allen, Texas

Shift Lead

January 2019 – November 2021

- Resolved customer complaints by effective communication, and strengthened the company connection with the community.
- Cultivated a successful night shift by ensuring a maximum amount of resources was available to their disposal.

Team Member

February 2018 – January 2019

- Provided high levels of customer service during high volume and fast paced operations.
- Took initiative to maintain a clean and organized environment, resulting in a streamlined flow of customers.

EDUCATION

App Academy Online

Curriculum of Study in Web Development (Javascript and Python)

August 2022 - January 2023

- Robust 1000-hour full stack software engineering course with <5% acceptance rate.
- Course included: Javascript, Data Structures and Algorithms (DS&A), Object Oriented Programming (OOP), Test Driven Development (TDD), Express, Sequelize, React, Redux, Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, and system architecture.

Allen High SchoolAllen, TexasDiplomaClass of 2020